cricket.com 2000-10-18

# PRIVACY STATEMENT | Communicate.com Network

Your Privacy

Communicate.com is committed to our visitors and to protecting their privacy. We value our visitors and endeavor to create an enjoyable and valuable experience when visiting our network of sites. The following Privacy Statement applies to all visitors to the Communicate.com network of sites, and to all referrals made by our visitors. 

What Information We Collect

The Communicate.com network of sites currently asks visitors for information in a variety of ways. First, there is a general survey posted that does not require the submission of any personal information. Second, when you enter our contest, we ask for your name, email address, age range, gender, country and zip/postal code to qualify as an entry. Third, we ask general interest questions in our survey questionnaire as a means for visitors to obtain additional entries into the contest. 

How the Customer Information is Used

Information collected from the contest entry, survey questions and through any other forum helps us develop the design, content, and features of our sites. We may also use the information we collect to email you every now and then about upcoming contests and developments on the sites within our network or news and/or promotions from our partners or to market new services and/or products that we believe will be of interest to you, in conjunction with our business partners. 

Customer Protection

Communicate.com takes all measures to provide a safe environment with security procedures in place to ensure proper storage and careful retrieval of information so that your personal information is secure and protected. 

What We Do with Your Information

Your privacy is a very sensitive subject for us and we take it very seriously. So our Privacy Statement is pretty simple. We will not sell, barter, give away or rent your personal information to any third party outside of Communicate.com Inc. and its properties. Communicate.com may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third parties, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. 

Cookies

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. We use cookies to store visitor's preferences, record session information, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, alert visitors to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to the site, record past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads and to customize web page content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends. 

Contests

Communicate.com runs contests across the network from time to time. Please refer to the Contest Rules and Regulations for details about each contest. 

Your Consent

By using our web site and submitting your information to the Communicate.com network, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Communicate.com Inc. If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. If you are not comfortable with any of the changes to our Privacy Statement, you will have the opportunity to unsubmit your information from our network at any time by emailing [unsubscribe@communicate.com](mailto:unsubscribe@communicate.com) and typing "unsubscribe" in the subject line. 

Links

Some sites within our network contain links to other external sites. Communicate.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. If you have a question about the Privacy Statement of those web sites, please visit them directly. 

Contacting Us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Statement, our site practices or your personal experience dealing with this web site, you can contact our offices at Suite 360-220 Cambie Street, Vancouver, BC, Canada, V6B 2M9, tel: 1.800.559.9188 or at [info@communicate.com](mailto:info@communicate.com). 
Communicate.com is committed to protecting your privacy. We value our visitors and endeavor to create an enjoyable and valuable experience when visiting our network of sites. The following Privacy Statement applies to all visitors to the Communicate.com network of sites, and to all referrals made by our visitors. 

## 1.0 What information we collect and how we use it

**1.1 User Registration**

To help recognize you and personalize your experiences on the Communicate.com Network we offer a general registration service. Registration requires that you provide us with your first name, last name, email address, age range, gender and country. You have the option to opt-in to any products or services we may offer. You can change, update, opt-out of services, or terminate your registration altogether at any time. 

Registering once with our network gives you access to the various services that you may choose to opt-in to, for example receiving marketing materials, free email, and access to forums. Registration also allows you to automatically populate our contest forms should you choose to participate. Your one user name and password will provide you access to all the services you have chosen on any of our web sites. And, we may from time to time also ask general interest questions in a survey questionnaire to help us understand what type of experience you would like to have when you visit a Communicate.com web site. 

If you do not wish to register, but would like to participate in a contest we may be offering, we will ask you for your name, email address, age range, gender, country and zip/postal code to qualify your entry, notify winners and deliver prizes related to our contests. If you so choose, we will use this information to notify you of special offers, new services, contests or surveys across our network of sites. 

If you would like to use the services of our network, your cookies must be turned on. You can auto-login, or login manually each time that you visit. 

**1.2 Collection, Use, and Disclosure**

We do not share, rent, trade or sell any of the personal information we currently hold with non-related third parties. We may choose to do so in the future.

We do, however, collect, and sometimes share with companies we have partnered with, anonymous statistical information about your visit to one or more of our sites. We may also share your personal information with third parties who manage activities on our web site, or market research firms that have been contracted by us. In such instances, we will ensure that they manage the information with appropriate care and due diligence.

Your personal information may be used for personalizing advertising or content. If you registered for a service and expressly asked us to send you information about contests or special offers, then we will use your information for that purpose. 

Your personal information may be disclosed without your consent if Communicate.com has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering with our rights, property, users, or anyone else who may be harmed by such activities. And, we will also disclose your information without your consent where we are required by law.

**1.3 Disposing of Information**

When we no longer need your information, or you have withdrawn your consent to use the information, we will securely erase, destroy, or make the information anonymous. 

**1.4 Your consent**

Consent means that you are aware, understand, and have expressly permitted Communicate.com to collect, use, re-use or disclose your personal information for the purpose(s) identified to you.  And, you understand that in providing us consent, you are permitting use of your personal information to ensure that we meet your reasonable expectations in providing services to you. For example, if you subscribe to a Communicate.com service, we may on occasion have to contact you regarding that service.

Where the information you are providing to us is sensitive, your consent must be expressed. For example, clicking on the submit button on a form that includes your personal information is considered expressed consent. Or, sending us an email requesting a product or service is considered consent. The manner in which your consent is granted may vary depending on the sensitivity of the information that you are providing to us. Where the information is less sensitive, implied consent will be considered appropriate. For example, when participating in a discussion forum, your username may be made available to other users. 

You can withdraw your consent (opt out) at any time by closing your account. To do this, select "modify account", then select "close account" and follow the instructions on the screen. You will receive an email confirmation which you must reply to in order to close your account.

If you have entered into an agreement with Communicate.com, withdrawal of your consent may be subject to legal or contractual restrictions. For example, if you enter a contest, you are bound by the rules and regulations associated with that promotion. In cases such as this, we will make a reasonable effort to inform you of any implications associated with withdrawing your consent.

**1.5 Kids Online & Privacy**

We do not currently have services for children under 13. If a child wants to use our services, the children's parent or guardian must register for our services and participate with the child.

**1.6 Accessing your personal information**

Where applicable, we will provide the means to update or modify your personal information online. Otherwise, you can request an update or modification of your information by sending us an email detailing the changes. Information regarding the existence, collection, use or disclosure of your personal information can be accessed by sending an email to [privacy_admin@en.communicate.com](mailto:privacy_admin@en.communicate.com).

We will provide the information to you within a reasonable period of time in a format that is easily understandable. We will only deny access if the information includes the information of another person, it is cost prohibitive, a security risk or it is proprietary, or where we are prohibited by law. Proof of your identify will be required before any information is disclosed to you, and depending on the nature of the request, you may be asked to incur the costs associated with supplying the information to you. You can also request our policies and procedures regarding the management of personal information. 

## 2.0 Links to external sites

Our privacy policy only applies to the Communicate.com network. It does not apply to non-network sites that you connect to from our sites. We recommend that you read their privacy policy to understand how they manage personal information. We choose our partners and sponsors carefully. However, we are not responsible for the content or practices of web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our sites. These links are provided as a service to our users. Unless otherwise stated, they do not constitute our endorsement, sponsorship or approval of their content, policies or practices.

## 3.0 "Cookies"

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information. We use cookies to reference stored information which may include:

  * a visitor's preferences; 
  * record session information; 
  * record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit; 
  * alert visitors to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to the site; 
  * record past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site; 
  * ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads; and 
  * to customize web page content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends. 

## 4.0 Log Files

Communicate.com uses IP addresses to identify and analyze trends, track user movements, administer the site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not link your IP address to your personal information.

## 5.0 Communicate.com Services and Your Privacy

**5.1 Send to a Friend Service**

If you use our Send-to-a-Friend service, we will use your friend's email address to send them a one time email inviting them to visit our website. 

**5.2 Free Email**

In addition to protecting identifiable personal information, Communicate.com will not monitor, edit, or disclose the contents of your private communications unless we are required to by law or in the good faith believe that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process, or to protect and defend the rights or property of Communicate.com. 

In using our free email service, you acknowledge and agree that Communicate.com neither endorses, nor assumes responsibility for any threatening, libelous, obscene, harassing or offensive material, any infringement of third party intellectual property rights, or any crime facilitated by the contents of any personal communications. 

You also acknowledge and understand that certain technical processing of email messages and their content may be required to send and receive messages; conform to connecting networks' technical requirements; conform to the limitations of the Service; or conform to other similar requirements. And, it is important for you to know that in the process of transmitting email messages, it is possible that your message may be lost or intercepted by a party other than Communicate.com.

Communicate.com will not send you any unsolicited information, including email, unless it is related to, for example, the maintenance of your account or a service you have selected.

**5.3 Chat & Forums**

Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information while using our chat or forum services, your information may be collected and used by others. Despite our efforts to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you choose to disclose online, and you do so at your own risk.

## 6.0 Security 

We exercise care and due diligence in managing, transmitting and securing personal information once we receive it. Your personal information is protected by safeguards that are appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. This may include restricted access to an office, secure access levels to databases, or the use of passwords and encryption. However, it is important for you to know that data transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure. Despite our efforts, unfortunately, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. 

If you register with any web site on the Communicate.com network, your account is password protected. Only you can access and view the information you have provided. We strongly encourage you not to divulge your password to anyone. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. We also recommend that you log-out of the network when you have finished your visit, and close your browser window when you have finished your work. Doing so will ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if your computer is accessible to others, such as in a library or Internet café.

## 7.0 General

**7.1 Changes to our Privacy Statement**

If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. If you are not comfortable with any of the changes to our Privacy Statement, you will have the opportunity to withdraw your information from our network at any time by selecting "modify account", then select "close account" and follow the instructions on the screen. You will receive an email confirmation, which you must reply to in order to close your account. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which it was collected. 

**7.2 Accountability at Communicate.com**

Accountability for the compliance with our privacy statement is the responsibility of our Privacy Officer, an employee of Communicate.com. 

If you have any questions about this statement, the practices of Communicate.com with respect to personal information, please contact us at [privacy_admin@en.communicate.com](mailto:privacy_admin@en.communicate.com) or write to:

Privacy Officer  
Communicate.com Inc.  
360-220 Cambie Street  
Vancouver, B.C.  
Canada  
V6B 2M9  

**7.3 Your Acceptance of These Terms**

Using any site on the Communicate.com network signifies your assent to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our sites. And, your continued use of our network sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.
